地上７４メートル
10 men ventured to cross
the beam of death...
死の鉄骨渡りに １０人の男が挑み
...74 meters above ground.
最後にカイジと佐原の
２人だけが残る
At the end, only Kaiji
and Sahara were left.
And Sahara...
そして佐原が…
佐原！
Sahara!
Heavens
佐原…
やった
Sahara...
I did it.
I did it...
やった！やった！
I did it!
やった やった！
佐原…
- I did it, I did it!
- Sahara!
I reached the goal!
ゴールだ 着いた
向こう側が俺の未来…
My future is
on the other side!
未来！
Future!
どうやって…
There's no handle.
How to open it?
いや ある
指の引っ掛かる所がある
No, it's here.
There's a finger hold here.
I will open this window!
開くぞ この窓
佐原… あ！
Sahara.
俺が先陣を切って…
I'll be in first place!
それは異様な光景だった
It was a strange scene.
窓の向こう側の人だかりが
People were gathered on
the other side of the window,
今 入らんとする佐原を取り囲み
笑っている
and laughing at Sahara
trying to get in.
They are the VIPs who were
watching the deadly crossing.
彼らは この鉄骨渡りのショーを
見物していたＶＩＰたち
ただ その笑いは佐原を迎え入れ
But their laughter was not to
welcome Sahara into their midst.
祝福しようなどという
それではなく
もっと別の何か…
別の何かを期待する笑い…
It was something else.
A laughter that was expecting
something else.
しかも 隣同士
皆 腕を組んでいる
Furthermore, all of them
were linking arms.
腕を組みつつ やや遠巻きに
うかがっている男たち
Linking arms and watching
at a distance from the window.
It was a dark anticipation.
その黒い期待…
A strange sight!
異様な光景…
よ よせ
Stop!
よせって
Stop, I said!
変だ 開けるな その窓
Something's not right.
Don't open that window!
What are you talking about?
何言ってんだよ
せっかく あともう少しで…
Just a little more
to go from here!
Stop!
よせ！
開く！
よせ 佐原！
Open!
Stop, Sahara! Stop!
よせ！
佐原！
Sahara!
佐原…
佐原！
空気圧…
It was air pressure!
A sudden gust caused by
the difference in air pressure...
ドーム球場などで経験する
...between inside and outside,
such as in Tokyo Dome.
内と外との気圧差による突風
佐原…
Sahara!
つまり この部屋は
もともと入り得ぬ部屋だったのだ
In other words,
this room was never meant to
be entered in the first place.
佐原
Sahara...
Sahara!
佐原…
佐原よ…
Sahara!
どうして どうして…
ひどい… ひどすぎる
Why? Why?
This is just too cruel!
こんな話があるか？
How could there be
such a thing?!
命からがら やっとの思いで
When he thought he'd barely
escaped with his life...
たどり着いたのに…
やり遂げたのに 突風…
And that he'd finally made it!
That gust!
あの風が もぎ取ってしまった
That gust wrenched
from his hands...
...a rare chance
at having a future.
せっかく手にした 奴の未来
Hope, and life...
希望 人生を…
佐原…
Sahara!
佐原
くそ くそ くそ
Darn it! Darn it!
くそ野郎
死ぬのか？
Will I die?
渡っても結局
あの突風で死ぬのか？
Will I cross and end up dead
from that blast of wind?
あ… それとも
If not...
この道を…
Should I walk back?
It's impossible.
There's no way.
とても無理だ できるわけない
てことは 結局…
Which means, in the end...
Death!
死！
奴らのあの笑い あの好奇心は
Those people's laughter,
their curiosity...
単なる死の見物じゃない
They aren't merely watching
a scene of death.
何というか もう少し別の何か…
There's something else.
人のミスや愚かさや不幸
It's a cruelty that laughs at
human folly, and the mistakes...
助かる道があるのに
その道を選べない
...that people make when
they don't choose the right path,
そんな人間をあざ笑う
そういう種類の残忍さ
and that path is
right before them.
Which means that
there must some way!
つまり… 何かある
生き残り方 抜け道
A way to survive;
an escape route!
There must be something.
There must be!
何か 何か…
あ… 人！
Someone?
上にも人がいる
なぜあんな所に？
There's someone up there too!
Why is he there?
いや 上で見物してても
おかしくないが
No, it's not strange to
watch from up there,
なぜ あの男だけが１人？
but why is he the only one?
Isolated by himself...
ただ１人 孤立して…
何だ あれは？
What's that?
向かってくる
It's moving towards here!
This is...
これは…
Glass?
ガラス？ガラスの道
A glass pathway!
Stairs...
階段
抜け道
An exit route...
これが あの突風を避け
This is the path to avoid that
blast of wind and reach the goal!
ゴールに至る起死回生の道
A turn-around situation
and route to survival!
逆転 生き残りの道か
こんな別ルートがあるなんて
Such an alternative route exists.
見えてしまえば明らかだ
明らかにある
As long as you catch sight of it,
this other route is obvious.
はっ… ある 佐原の側にも
It's over at Sahara's side too.
何てことだ
こんなものが見えなかったなんて
What going on?
How could he not have seen it?
いや 思えば
気がつくような状況になかった
No. Considering our situation,
we could never have known.
スタート地点からは
遠すぎて確認できないし
It's too far away to be
seen from the starting point.
And while crossing, we were in
no condition to have noticed.
途中はそんなことに
気が回る状況になかった
目の前の道を
ただ行くのが精いっぱい
Trying to move forward alone
drove us to our wit's end.
心理的に死角
A psychological blind spot...
そして 佐原のように
窓までたどり着いてしまえば
And upon reaching that
window like Sahara,
今度は位置的に死角
it's a blind spot where you'd
mistake the window as the goal,
窓を開ければゴールという時に
and not notice anything behind.
自分の後ろに気を回す者はいない
唯一 気がつき得るのは この地点
At this spot, all you
would see is the goal.
だが あともう少しでゴール
気持ちは そのことでいっぱいだ
And you'd perceive that it's
only a short distance away.
結局 今の俺のように
So, unless in my position
of having lost one's goal...
ゴールを失って 立ち往生
...and not knowing what to do,
you would never see it.
どうしたものかと
途方に暮れなければ気がつかない
つまり
一度 失望した者にしか見えない…
In other words, only those who
have lost hope once can be saved.
そんな救い
救い？
Saved?!
しかし だからといって
絶対に安全だとは言えない
Even so, there is
no guaranteed safety.
ワナかもしれない
It might be a trap!
But...
が しかし…
しかし やるしかない
But I have to do it!
俺には今 ほかに選択肢などない
Right now,
I have no other choice!
I did it!
やった！
やった やった やった
I did it! I did it! I did it!
やった！
I've won!
賭けに勝った
I won the gamble!
勝った 勝ったんだ
I won!
I won! It's the goal! Goal!
ゴール… ゴールだ
あ… 開いた
It opened!
開いた 開いた
着いた 着いたんだよな
Have I reached?
I've reached, haven't I?
ゴール… ゴールだ！
It's the goal! The goal!
コングラチュレーションズ
おめでとう
Congratulations.
完走おめでとう
やあ おめでとう
Congrats on your finish.
Congratulations.
利根川！
Tonegawa!
ふふふ… 見事 見事
Wonderful, wonderful.
実に見事な完走だ
What a splendid finish.
すばらしい おめでとう
How fantastic. Congratulations.
よしやがれ 何がめでたい？
Stop it!
What's there to congratulate?!
どこが めでたいんだ？ええ？
何人死んだと思ってんだ
ふざけるな！
How many people
do you think have died?!
Stop messing around!
出せよ ろくでもない
おためごかしなんか要らねえ
Pay up!
I don't need your
useless congratulations!
金だ 金…
Give me the money! Money!
出せ…
Pay up!
石田さん 佐原…
Ishida...
Sahara...
ほら２枚
Here's two tickets!
残念だが そのチケットは無効だ
I'm sorry but
those tickets are void.
橋の途中で その効力を失った
Their validity was lost
during the crossing.
失ったって… あ…
Lost?!
タイムオーバー？
The time ran out?
バカな まだ時間はあるはずだ
No way!
There's still time left!
ふふふ… 確かにその点は問題ないが
忘れたのか？
Indeed, there's no problem there.
But have you forgotten something?
お前が言い出したのだぞ
It's what you said.
Huh?
利根川 切れ 電流を！
Tonegawa! Cut the power!
金は要らない 中止だ 中止！
You can keep your money!
The deal is off!
我々はお前の願いを聞き入れ
We acceded to your request
and turned off the power.
あの後 電流を切ったのだ
もっとも
多少 電流を切るのが遅れて
But due to some delay,
痛ましい犠牲者も出たがな
some were victimised as a result.
ということだ
So, that's that.
つまり お前は自ら放棄したんだ
In other words,
you willingly forfeited...
権利を ふふふ…
...your own right to the prize.
ふざけるな てめえ！
Don't mess with me, you scum!
そんなこと 通じるか！
That's unacceptable!
切るならすぐ切れ 汚ねえぞ
You should have cut
the power at once!
You're despicable!
このチケットが紙くずなら
何のために…
What was the purpose of going
through that for scrap paper?!
何のために？
What for?!
許せるか
許せるかよ そんなペテン
Unforgivable!
This fraud is unforgivable!
殺す 利根川！
I'll kill you, Tonegawa!
My, my.
利根川
Tonegawa.
Sir.
一理あるではないか
Don't his words
make some sense?
その子の言い分にも
確かに電流は
すぐ切るべきだったし
Indeed, we should have cut
the power immediately.
それが遅れて事故が起きた以上
The accidents that occurred
due to our delay...
我々にも いくばくかの
責任はある… のう
...are partly our responsibility,
don't you think?
利根川
Tonegawa, give this boy
another chance.
この子にもう一度
チャンスをあげなさい
種目は そう…
As for the event...
Ｅカードが面白かろう
E-Card should be interesting.
Ｅカード？
Yes.
E-Card?
何だ Ｅカードって？
What is this E-Card?
それに この男
And who is this guy who calls
Tonegawa by name?
利根川を呼び捨てにする
この男は…
あ… あの時の…
From that time!
こいつがドン 元締めなのか？
This guy's the head?
The mastermind...
この悪魔じみたギャンブルの？
...behind this devilish bridge!
最近の若者は
どうしようもないクズばかりだが
Although young ones these
days are mostly trash,
君は少しはマシなようだ
you seem to be a bit better.
あの橋を渡りきっただけでも
その片りんはうかがえる
That crossing gave me
a glimpse of your worth.
ははは… 実に興味深い
You are indeed interesting.
なかなか おらんからな
君のようなタイプは
People like you are
an uncommon type.
ぜひ量りたいものだ 君の容量を
A worthy specimen indeed.
Your capacity,
reflexes, endurance...
つまり 心の瞬発力 持久力
その性質 傾向を
Also, your nature and inclination.
分かるかな？
Do you understand?
その「はかり」として
最も効果的な方法が
E-Card is the most effective
way to gauge all of that.
Ｅカード
もしこのＥカードで
If you can beat the opponents
I have selected...
わしの推薦した相手を
上回るようなことになれば
...for this game of E-Card,
２０００万はおろか
you can get not just 20 million
but even up to 100 million.
１億という金を得ることもできる
むろんそれは それ相当の
ハイリスクをくぐってのことだが
Of course, there's a relatively
high level of risk involved.
そんなリスクがイヤなら
But if you don't wish
to take that risk,
ノーリスクで
４～５０万拾うこともできる
you can get four to
five million at no risk.
言うなれば これは
完走したのに金を得られない
Putting it in another way,
this is a charity for you...
君に対する慈悲…
...who obtained nothing
despite having finished.
だが強要はせん 君の自由だ
But I will not force you.
It's your choice.
このまま空手で帰るもよし
It's fine if you go back
with nothing.
気力を掘り起こし
もうひと勝負するもよし
If you gather up your courage
to play again, it's also fine.
もしやると言うのなら案内しよう
If you are in,
then let us guide you...
プレイルームへな
...to the playroom.
このままでは帰れない
I can't go back like this!
空手じゃダメだ
I can't go back with nothing.
空手で帰ったら 俺たちが
やってきたことがすべて無為
If I do, all that we have done
until now would go to waste!
あんなペテン師じみた詭弁で
すべてを ほごにされてたまるか
I won't throw it all away...
...by letting that cheat
get away with it!
引き下がれない
I will not retreat!
何としてもチケット分
２０００万 もぎ取ってやる
I must recover the tickets'
worth of 20 million!
１本目の橋での脱落者
墜落した者たちだ
These are the ones who
fell from the first bridge.
We paid them to stay
as guests for a while.
いくばくかのゲスト料を出して
残っていただいた
戒めのためにな
As a warning.
この地上は苦しみのたうつ
怨嗟の声にあふれておる
This earth is filled
with grieving voices.
１０人 １００人のうめきが
The groans of tens
or even hundreds...
１人の豊かな生活を支えておる
...support the lives of
plenty of individuals.
それが この世の仕組み
That is the way of the world.
わしはその現実を認識し
We recognise that and we tell
this to ourselves all the time.
常に自らに言い聞かせておる
どんなことがあろうと
絶対に人は助けぬとな
No matter what, we will
definitely not help anyone.
むろん金はある
湯水のようにあるが
Of course, we have the money
and it's simple for us...
わしは助けん
But I will not help.
なぜだか分かるか？
Do you know why?
なぜって…
Why?
実にここ… ここが肝心
Actually, this is
the important part.
何てことを！
へへへ… カイジ君 ここだ
What are you doing?
Kaiji, over here!
いやー！
まさにここ
Right here!
やめろ
Stop!
It's as you see.
見てのとおりだ
折れた足をいじられると
彼は痛いが
Even though he's in pain when
his broken leg is agitated,
わしは痛まない
I don't feel it.
カイジ君も痛くはなかろう
You don't feel the pain either.
この一事だ この一事だけが真実
Just this.
This is the only truth.
いいのだよ
It's fine.
It doesn't matter
how much others suffer.
他人がどう苦しもうと
全く問題ない
唯一 問題なのは自分の幸福だけ
それに…
The only thing that matters
is your own happiness.
Besides...
それに この男はもっと
してほしかったに違いないのだ
This man here must
certainly want more suffering.
- Hey you.
- Yes!
おい
あ… 金 金… 俺の金…
Money... money... my money!
わしがサービスしてやった者には
They were told that those who
get some service from me...
ボーナスを出すと
事前に伝えてある
...will be paid a bonus.
For just that small sum of
money before their eyes,
人はな
目の前のわずかな金のために
相当なことには耐えられるのだ
people can endure a lot.
その特性を金持ちは利用し
The rich make use
of that quality...
生涯かしずかれ 安楽に暮らす
...to lead comfortable lives,
being waited upon by others.
王は１人で王になるわけではない
A king is not king
on his own.
金など要らぬと貧しき者どもが
結束して反抗すれば
If the poor unite and rebel,
declaring that they
don't need money,
王もまた消えるのだ
the king will be vanquished.
しかし 貧乏人は王になろうと
金を求め
But the poor pursue money
in the hopes of becoming king.
逆に 今いる王の存在を
より盤石にする
This strengthens the
existence of the current king.
そういう不毛なパラドックスから
出られない
As long you don't break out
of that fruitless paradox...
金を欲している以上…
...of wanting money,
王は倒せぬ
you can never overthrow the king
but be chained forever.
縛られ続ける
王も暴動が起きぬよう
The king too,
tries to prevent revolt...
...by giving everyone a relative
sense of abundance and wealth.
皆 そこそこ豊かな気分で
いられるよう 注意しておる
実際は どんなに
こき使っていようともな
No matter how much
he is using them in reality.
これからやるゲームは
言うなれば そういう社会の縮図
The game that will be played
from now is, in other words,
the microcosm of society.
利根川 あとは頼む
Tonegawa, take care of the rest.
Yes, Sir!
こっちだ
This way.
簡単だ カイジ
It's simple, Kaiji.
今回のＥカード
In E-Card, both persons
have 10 cards each.
使うカードは２人で１０枚
その内訳は この３種
The breakdown consists
of three types.
市民 皇帝 そして奴隷
Citizen.
Emperor.
And Slave!
そして カイジに
想像を絶する条件が提示される
And then Kaiji was
presented with conditions...
...that he never
could have imagined.
そのＥカードとは…
The truth behind E-Card!
次回 「怒髪」
Next, Fury.